可以带我们进入他的秘密实验室
That could lead us to his secret lab.
我们被攻击了
We were attacked.
被谁
By who?
我还指望你告诉我
I was hoping you could tell me.
一小时内让机器运作起来
Get the device operational within one hour
否则我就杀了他
Or I will kill him.
懂么
Do you understand?
你们早就找到了attero设备
Somehow, you've found the attero device.
什么
What?
我们出不去了
We're locked in.
等等  这个设备有问题  很严重很危险
Wait, there's a very dangerous, serious problem with the device,
我们得和你上司谈谈
And we need to talk to your boss--
如果能量再继续堆积
If the power continues to build like this,
星门将会超过负荷
The gate will reach critical overload
最终将导致爆炸
And most certainly explode.
所有人撤离
Everyone that doesn't need to be here,
到城市另一边
Get to the edge of the city.
这还不够
It's not enough.
快点
Move quickly.
我们得把人群
We have to get everyone
撤离至塔底
To the lower levels of the tower
以确保每个人...
To make sure that everyone will be--
谢帕德中校  你没事吧
Colonel sheppard, are you all right?
约翰
John?
泰勒
Teyla!
上面有几个人
How many were up there?
两个
Two.
我去找人来
I'll go get my people.
约翰
John?!
我走时他们就在这儿
They were right here when I left them.
如果爆炸产生的热量过大
If the explosion was hot enough,
我们也许什么都找不到
There might not be anything left for us to find.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
约翰
John!
我们没躲好
We didn't take cover.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
到底怎么样
我的耳朵
My ears...
有玻璃插到我背上了
I think I've got a some glass in my back.
玛丽
Marie...
星门没保住  控制室也完了
We lost the stargate, we lost the control room.
真糟糕
That's bad.
你在就好
But we did not lose you.
不幸中的万幸
That's good.
好了
Okay.
您要求的部队已经传送上船
All the troops you've requested have beamed onboard.
叫他们把剩下的人
Have them round up the rest of the humans
通通赶到停泊舱软禁起来
And confine them to one of the hangar bays.
通知母舰在这儿等
Inform our hive to wait for us here,
无论如何
And under no circumstances
也不能启动超光速推进系统
Are they to activate their hyperdrive.
遵命
Yes.
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
亚特兰蒂斯
Atlantis.
去找班克斯和她的组员
I need you to get banks and her team
在毁坏区建一个副控制室
To set up an auxiliary control room below the damaged areas.
他们已经着手了  你怎么样
They've already begun. how are you?
至少还活着
I'm alive.
已经不错了
You know, that's good for now.
对这一切我还是一头雾水
I still do not understand what happened.
星门爆炸了
The gate blew up.
我多少也猜到了
That much I surmised.
为什么
But why?
不知道
I don't know.
该死的麦凯哪儿去了  要找他时就不见了
Where the hell's mckay when you need him, huh?
好吧  这个设备
All right, so the device
制造出极其特别的子空间"干扰"
Creates a very specific subspace "turbulence"
使幽灵人无法
That makes it impossible
启动超光速推进系统
For the wraith to operate their hyperdrives.
你刚刚说过了
You said that already.
但存在副作用
But there's a side effect.
杰纳斯提到的那个"未知副作用"
The "unforeseen" one that janus mentions.
是啊  这里肯定见不着
Yeah, well, it's certainly not seen here
这破星球连个星门都没有
Because there's no stargate on this planet.
你到底想说什么  罗德尼
What's the point, rodney?
尽管这个子空间干扰
Although the subspace turbulence
只对幽灵的超光速推进系统产生影响
Only affects the wraith's hyperdrive systems,
它所产生的辐射也是很危险的
It creates a very dangerous type of radiation
那个
That, well...
也会扰乱对星门的基本操作
The messes with the basic operation of the stargates.
星门?  对所有的都有影响吗
Stargates? what, as in all of them?
是的  飞马星系网络系统里的所有星门
All of the stargates in the pegasus network, yes.
你刚刚说"扰乱"  什么意思
And when you say "messes with," you mean what?
听着  一旦启动
Look, when dialed,
星门内部就会积蓄能量
Power will build up inside the gate
直到超过负荷
Until it overloads.
你是说
So you're saying
只要杰纳斯的装置在运行
That as long as this janus device is running,
一旦有人开启了星门
Every time someone dials a gate in the entire galaxy--
就会爆炸
It'll explode.
如果不关掉的话
Millions of people will die
成千上万人就会死于非命
If we don't shut that thing down.
醒得正是时候  伍尔希先生
Good timing, mr. woolsey.
听着  我不知道你们到底误解了什么
Look, I don't know what it is you think we've done,
但我保证
But I assure you--
带我们离开超空间
Take us out of hyperspace.
我们还没抵达亚特兰蒂斯
We haven't arrived at atlantis yet.
亚特兰蒂斯
Atlantis?
已经进入可通信范围
We're within communications range.
不过我们不想离得太近
We don't want to get too close.
带我们出去
Take us out.
我还指望你意识到了呢
I was hoping you'd be awake for this.
一切正常了吗
Well, are we up and running?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我们已将城里的主要控制器
We've routed all the city's main controls
弄到这个房间里了
Into this room.
总算有点样子了
At least we're not blind anymore.
是啊  但我们损失惨重
No, but we're severely crippled.
没有星门
Without the gate
没法靠近代达罗斯号
Or the ability to reach the daedalus,
就无法接近M6H-987
We have no way of getting to m6h-987
也无法营救罗德尼和杰克森博士
Or rescuing rodney and dr. jackson.
那我们怎么办
What should we do?
谁能连上代达罗斯号我就给他5块钱
5 bucks to anyone who figures out how to contact  daedalus.
谢帕德中校
Uh, colonel sheppard?
你有办法了  班克斯?
You got an idea, banks?
没有  但处在子空间的代达罗斯号在呼叫我们
Well, no, but I am being hailed by the  daedalus on subspace.
这算吗
Does that count?
技术上说这不是你的点子
Technically that's not your idea,
但是好极了
But good enough.
连接到大屏幕上
Put 'em on screen.
一会儿把钱给你
I'll pay you later.
代达罗斯号  很高兴...
Daedalus, it's good to, uh--
谢帕德中校
Colonel sheppard.
到底发生了什么
What the hell's going on?
卡德威尔在哪儿
Where's caldwell?
我把他们都免职了
I'm afraid I had to relieve him and his crew of duty.
他离我们有多远
How close are they?
乘飞船去还到不了
Not close enough to go by jumper.
别担心
Don't worry,
我很愿意
I'm more than willing
把船和船员都还给你们
To return this ship and its crew to you.
与之交换的是
In exchange for what?
被你们激活的设备
You've activated the attero device.
请给我关了
I need you to shut it down
并立刻告诉我它的位置
And give me its location immediately.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你以前很聪明的
It was very clever of you,
把我的船引诱到
Luring me and my ship
子空间去
Out into the open
然后看看是否管用
So you could see for yourself if it worked.
什么是否管用
If what worked?
我承认  从某种程度上来说我印象深刻
I have to admit, in a way I'm impressed.
一万年前  我眼睁睁的看着
I was there 10,000 years ago
古人第一次使用attero设备
When the ancients first tried to use it,
但他们最终没能坚持
But they didn't have the stomach to leave it on
因为他们意识到
Once they realized
许多宝贵的星门
How many of their precious stargates
因此毁于一旦
It would destroy...
造成无辜生命的流逝
How many humans it would kill.
听上去像杰纳斯会干的事
Sounds like something janus would have worked on.
告诉我设备的位置
Give me the location of the attero device,
一旦将其摧毁
And once I have destroyed it,
我就把船员还给你
I will return this crew to you.
听着  不是你想得那样
Look, it's not what you think.
我们跟这事没关系
We have nothing to do with this.
你们每浪费一分钟
Every minute that goes by
不告诉我设备在哪儿
Without you telling me where this device is,
就有一个队员被杀
I will kill a member of your expedition.
现在开始计时
Your time starts now.
给我点时间
Give us a second.
我觉得不能现在就开始计时
I don't think this should count toward the minute.
我是说  目前为止他还没
I-- I mean, he didn't say no...
说不
Yet.
有没有可能...  那东西叫啥
What are the odds that-- what's this thing called?
attero设备
Uh, attero device.
有没有可能
What are the odds
那玩意是在罗德尼开启的
That this thing was at the other end
子空间连接的另一端
Of the subspace link that rodney opened
当他进入实验室时
When he went to that lab?
在M6h-987?  很有可能
M6h-987? very likely.
也很有可能
It's also very likely
他和杰克森博士就是在那儿被抓的
That's where he and dr. jackson were taken.
一定是杰纳斯在幽灵战争期间
It must be a weapon that janus developed
开发的武器
During the wraith war.
能炸飞星门的武器?
A weapon to blow up stargates?
我很怀疑这是它的原型
I doubt that was its original design.
貌似这个战略不太有效
It doesn't seem like an effective strategy.
极其讨厌的副作用
So, a nasty side effect.
这也许是他们停产的原因
That's probably why they stopped production.
无论他们从实验室拿走了什么
Whatever the aliens took from the lab
用来再次激活设备
Allowed them to reactivate it again.
无论是什么
Whatever it is,
托德貌似一定要阻止它
Todd seems pretty keen to stop it,
不惜冒险劫持代达罗斯号
Enough to risk taking the  daedalus.
是啊  但我们不能给他地址
Yes, but we can't give him the address.
如果他弄到手
If he gets it,
就会毁掉一切阻止他的人
He'll destroy everything in his path,
包括罗德尼和杰克森博士
Including rodney and dr. jackson.
约翰  我们别无选择
John, we don't have a choice.
我们的防护盾
Our shield was able
抗得住爆炸的冲击
To take the brunt of the explosion,
但要是发生在其它星球上
But if this is happening on other worlds,
这会害死千千万万的人
It could kill millions.
连线吧
Put 'em back on.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
我们不是幕后的主使者
We're not the ones behind this.
很好
Very well.
等一下
W-w-wait!
我是说  我们不是幕后主使者
I said, we're not the ones behind this,
但是我们有你想要的东西
But we may have what you need.
昨天亚特兰蒂斯被一个
Atlantis was attacked yesterday,
我们从来没有遇到过的种族攻击了
By a race we have not encountered before.
他们偷走了一部分古人科技
They stole a piece of ancient technology.
我们认为这是这个attero设备
We believe this could be a component
的组成部分
To this attero device.
我们成功地找到了他们
We managed to track them.
你过来  带上我  我会亲自带你去那里
You swing by here, pick me up, I will take you there myself.
然后给你创造机会伙同飞弹
And give you the chance to take out my hyperdrive
去抢走我的超光速推进器?
With one of your drones?
我觉得不可能
I think not.
为什么我要这么做
Why would I do that?
现在你是这个星系中仅剩的
Right now, you're one of
的少数人之中的一员
the few people in the galaxy
拥有这可以解决这个问题的飞船
With a ship capable of dealing with this problem.
我希望就这么一直保持下去
And I intend to keep it that way.
约翰·谢帕德  把你们掌握的坐标传过来
John sheppard, transmit the coordinates
要不然我就当这你们的面
Or I will feed on mr. woolsey
吃掉伍尔希先生
Before your eyes!
传过去吧
Do it.
我们拿到了
We have it.
后会有期
We'll be in touch.
你真的觉得这可行吗
You really think that's going to work?
难道你有更好的方法?
You got a better idea?
我们在太空船上
We're on a space ship.
这些门的设计是密不透风的
Those doors are designed to be airtight.
就是说连空气
That means something as tiny as air
都进不去
Can't even get through.
难道你觉得你能把它扒开吗
How do you think you will?
对啊  我比空气大多了
Yeah, well, I'm a lot bigger than air.
...这正是我的意思
Yeah... that's kind of my point.
看到了吧
See?
若楠
Ronon!
你还好吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
好咧  来吧
All right. come on.
等一下  你想怎样  我们要去哪
Wait. what's our plan? where are we going?
找到进入的梯子
Get to an access ladder,
去到二楼的工程舱
Head down two floors to the engineering rooms.
然后我们把这飞船弄瘫
Then we cripple the ship.
你知道怎么做这些事吗
You... know how to do all that?
知道啊  你不知道吗
Yeah. don't you?
不是很清楚
Not really.
学着点哈
Watch and learn.
超空间之门开启
Hyperspace window opening.
你觉得是托德改变主意了吗
Think todd changed his mind?
他可能已经发现我们有多没用了吧
He might have realized just how crippled we are.
有人呼叫
We're being hailed.
接进来
Put it up.
我的名字是堪塔娜·拉布雷  我是太空游历者
My name is katana labrea. I'm a traveler.
拉林派我来的
Larrin sent me.
一切都还好吗
Well, is everything all right?
事实上  不好
No, as a matter of fact, it's not.
拉林希望你能告诉我们
Larrin was hoping you could tell us
为什么星门爆炸了
Why the stargates are blowing up.
你  跟我来
You. come with me.
我  为啥
Me? why?
我们俩都跟你走  不用那枪指着我们
Whoa. we'll both go. no need for that.
不是你
No.
我猜...可能轮到你
I guess it... just must be your turn
去那个"健身室"了
To use the fitness room.
是啊
Right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你也是
You too.
这是我们在行星
It was the first colony we'd built
第一次开辟的一块聚居地
On the surface of a planet
经过了这些世代
In a hundred generations,
它突然升高了
And it was leveled in an instant.
那时候我还在轨道中
I was in orbit when it happened.
我可以从太空中看到整个的爆炸过程
We could see the explosion from space.
我从来没用看过比这个威力更大的东西了
I've never witnessed anything that powerful.
嗯  这个门是用naquadah做成的
Mm. the gates are made of naquadah.
当它们不稳定时
When they become unstable,
所造成的爆炸是无法估量的
The size of the explosion is unimaginable.
我们死了3000人
We lost 3,000 people
还有两艘船
And two ships,
包括我们古人飞船
Including our ancient vessel.
拉林本来想自己来的  但是
Larrin would have come herself, but--
不用了  我想她现在已经够忙的了
No, I'm sure she's got her hands full.
听着  这些异族人  不管他们是谁
Look, these aliens or whoever they are,
他们绑架了我们两个伙伴
They have two of our people hostage.
必须阻止他们
They need to be stopped.
我们已经知道他们的方位坐标了  可是我们没用飞船
We have coordinates, but... we have no ship.
那么我想我来得刚刚好
Then I guess I got here just in time.
这正是我想要听到的
That's what I wanted to hear.
泽兰卡  你跟我来
Zelenka, you're with me.
约翰...
John--
泰勒  我需要你守在这里  好吗
Teyla, I need you to stay here, all right?
如果托德的奸计得逞
The second todd's done,
就没有人能阻止他
There's nothing stopping him
不止是让飞船改变方向
From turning that ship around
他甚至会冲着亚特兰蒂斯而来
And making a run at Atlantis.
我需要有一个我可以信任的人守着这里
I need somebody I can trust to stay in charge here.
祝你好运
Good luck.
我去把门锁上
I locked the door.
这不需要太多时间的
This won't take long.
那么我们要怎么做
So what do we do?
让整个控制系统瘫痪
Bring up the main control systems
还是一个个来
And disable them one by one?
有一个好方法
That's one way to go.
你还得把它们锁在主机之外
Well, you'd have to lock them out of the mainframe, though.
不然的话他们可以东山再起的
Otherwise they could just turn them back on again.
你有密码之类的东西吗
Do you have some sort of a passcode
让我们可以一次性
To make sure they're locked out
锁定系统
Once and for all?
没哦
Nope.
那你到底在想什么
Well, then, what are you thinking?
我们和超空间失去连接了
We just dropped out of hyperspace.
我知道
I see that, yes.
为什么
Why?
我不清楚
I'm not sure.
我们的电脑认为  这是战争损坏
The computer seems to think it's due to battle damage.
领部队去工程舱
Get our troops down to the engineering room.
有人在破坏飞船
Someone's sabotaging this ship.
你在干什么?
Wh-- what are you doing?
让飞船瘫痪啊
Disabling the ship.
我们不能就这样轰掉主系统
You can't just blast away at vital systems like that!
如果把这艘船的生命供给系统毁掉怎么办
What if you take out the life support system?
别担心
Don't worry.
生命供给系统在那一块
The life support system is that tray.
这个我还是很确定的
At least, I'm pretty sure it is.
行了  我们已经和超空间断开了
Okay, we're out of hyperspace.
这就够了  来吧
That's enough. come on.
你想跟我谈谈吗
You wish to speak to me?
你是首领吗
You're the leader?
我们得马上停了这设备
You need to shut this device down Immediately.
我不会这么做的
No, I do not.
好吧  我能理解为什么你们要毁灭幽灵人
Okay, look, I understand wanting to destroy the wraith.
真的
I do.
可是不能这么做
But this isn't the way.
我不同意
I disagree.
我不知道你懂不懂
Okay, I don't know if you're aware of this or not,
这个仪器有致命的副作用
But this device has a serious side effect.
在它启动的时候星门会爆炸
It makes stargates explode when they're activated.
我们又不用星门
We do not use the stargates.
好吧
Okay.
可是其它人要用
But lots of other people do.
他们的生死与我们无关
They are of no concern to us.
所以你们就任由他们这么死掉
So you're just going to let them die,
这星系里千千万万的人们?
Millions of people, across the galaxy?
你们不比幽灵人好到哪里去
You're no better than the wraith.
可能吧  可这是我们唯一的选择
Perhaps. but we have little choice.
为什么
Why?
我们的行星正在消亡
Our planet is dying.
它不再适合我们的生存了
It can no longer sustain us.
世世代代以来这是第一次
For the first time in countless generations,
我们必须再一次冒险进入飞马星系
We must venture out into this galaxy again,
而它现在被幽灵人统治着
A galaxy controlled by the wraith.
不是他们死  就是我们亡
If we do not destroy them, they will destroy us.
我们必须要这么做
This is the way it must be.
幽灵人比我们抢先一步了
The wraith are ahead of us.
他们一到那个行星
As soon as they get to that planet,
就会动用所有的武器
They'll open up with everything they've got.
相信我  他们才不会去管老百姓的死活
Trust me, they ain't going to be worried about collateral damage.
想要营救我们朋友的唯一的机会
The only chance we have to save our friends
就是要赶在幽灵人前头到达那里
Is to get there first.
你想要快一点吗
You want speed?
那你们来对地方了
You've come to the right place.
这就是你们的工程舱?
This is your engineering room?
是的
That's right.
虽然看起来不像
It may not look like much,
相信我
But trust me,
我们可以超过很多船队
We can outrun most anything in the traveler fleet.
米拉?
Mila?
这是谢帕德中校和泽兰卡博士
This is colonel sheppard and dr. zelenka.
他们从亚特兰蒂斯来的
They're from atlantis.
米拉是我们的主工程师
Mila's our chief engineer.
她一定没有16岁
She can't be more than 16 years old.
事实上  她只有15岁
15, actually.
从她4岁起
She's been working on ships
她就开始在这里工作了
Since she was four.
我们要飞得越快越好
We need to get where we're going as fast as possible.
我希望你竭尽所能
I want you to do whatever you can
去最大化超光速推进器的功率
To maximize hyperdrive output.
没问题
No problem.
嗯  泽兰卡
You know, uh, zelenka
也懂得一些超光速推进器方面的东西
Knows a thing or two about hyperdrives himself.
我相信他很乐意帮忙的
I'm sure he'd be happy to give you a hand.
天知道能不能帮的上
Who knows,
可能可以学到些东西
Maybe you'll learn a thing or two.
损害很厉害
The damage is significant.
开始维修
Begin repairs.
attero设备运作中的每一分钟
Every second The attero device is active,
我们都在不停的失去越来越多的同盟
We risk losing more and more of our alliance.
我已经注意到了
It has come to my attention
已经有某些原先的船员
That someone from the original crew
逃了出来
Has eluded capture.
你们的自由已经严重影响到我们
Your freedom has become a nuisance.
立刻自首
Turn yourself in immediately
不然我就杀掉你们的朋友
Or we will begin killing off your friends
一个接一个
One by one.
给你三分钟
You have three minutes to comply.
他在虚张声势
He's bluffing.
才不是
No, he's not.
你去哪里
Where are you going?
我去自首
I'm turning myself in.
你不能这么做
No, you're not.
他要开始大开杀戒
He's going to start killing people.
他会杀了你
He's going to kill you.
希望不会
Well, I hope not.
为了船上的人
We need to get armed,
我们得武装起来  夺回飞船控制权
Free these people, and take this ship back.
正是
Exactly.
我去自首  他就以为我们全被他抓起来了
I turn myself in, and he'll think he's got us all.
这样你就可以争取时间
It buys you the time you need
做你该做的
To do what you've got to do.
不  我不会让你冒这个险
No. no, I'm not letting you do it.
若楠  听我说
Ronon, listen to me--
珍妮弗
Jennifer,
不行
No.
好的
Okay.
你说得对
You're right.
好的
Okay.
跟我来
Come on.
反正我们也快到了
We're almost there anyways.
这事关千千万万人们的性命
We're talking about the deaths of millions of people.
你怎能如此冷酷无情
How can you be so callous?
你还惧怕什么
And what is it you're so afraid of?
什么你还穿着战斗的盔甲
Why-- why are you still in your battle armor?
我伤不了你
I can't hurt you.
我知道你不是人类
I know you're not human.
也决不是幽灵人
You're definitely not wraith.
如若你是古人
And if you were an ancient,
你根本不需要我们帮你
You wouldn't have needed our help
激活装置
To activate the device.
你究竟是何方神圣
So... what are you?
你是阿斯加德族的
you are asgard?
你以前见过我们这一种族的吗
You've encountered our kind before?
不仅仅是见过
No, not just encountered.
还共事过
I've worked with them,
还和其中几个成了朋友
Even called a few of them my friends.
的确
Indeed.
当然  我所认识的阿斯加德
Of course, the asgard I knew were a noble race
是个乐于帮助人类的
Who actually helped the human population
高贵种族
In my galaxy.
那他们现在在何方
And where are they now?
都死了
Dead.
但这不是我们的错
But that had nothing to do with us.
你确定?
Are you certain?
他们是克隆人
They were clones--
一代一代  无限复制
Copies of copies of copies, going back generations,
结果  他们遭受不可逆转的基因退化的作用
And they suffered irreversible genetic degradation as a result.
这点你早就得知
But you probably already know that.
当然
Of course,
我们也是复制人
Because we are clones as well,
遵循削弱补偿规律
Subject to the same law of diminishing returns.
至少  我们活得很好
And yet, we are still very much alive.
你把问题解决了?
So, what, you solved the problem?
不完全是
Not entirely.
但我们曾经进行过
But once we were able
一次无干扰的试验
To conduct our research without interference,
因此取得巨大的成果
We made significant progress.
用活人试验
Research on humans...
因为人类的生理构造
Because our physiology is similar
和你们祖先的相似
To what yours used to be.
正是如此
Precisely.
我收回刚才的话
I take that back.
我以前见过像你一样的阿斯加德族
I have met an asgard like you before.
他叫洛基
His name was loki,
他也是用活人做试验
And he was experimenting on humans too,
后来被拘捕了
Until he was caught
并被带到阿斯加德高等法院审判
And brought to justice by the asgard high council.
因为他们不信奉"为求目的  不择手段"这一真理
Because they did not believe the ends justified the means.
是的
That's right.
看看他们的下场
And look where it got them.
进展如何
Well, how's it coming?
这情况常有
It does that sometimes.
别介意
Don't let it bother you.
听着  我们现在做的事
Listen, what we are doing here
冒险之极
Is not safe.
还有什么新消息
What else is new?
她这样驾驶  让飞船损耗很大
She is pushing this ship well past its boundaries.
这不是我们正需要的吗
That's kind of what we asked for, no?
如果我们不在托德之前
If we don't get rodney and danny back
救出罗德尼和丹尼
Before todd gets there,
他们就死定了
They're goners.
这是我所见的最原始的
This is the crudest hyperdrive system
超光速推进系统了
I've ever encountered.
都是用不入流的配件装配起来的
It is cobbled together from mismatching components.
能用粗劣的材料建造出这样的飞船
She's got to be pretty smart to put a hyperdrive together
不就是天才所为吗
With mismatched parts.
飞船快要着火了
She's going to burn it up.
飞出超空间后  很有可能
Once out of hyperspace, there's a high possibility
系统就瘫痪了
We won't be able to engage the drive again.
到时再说吧
Let's worry about that when we get there.
那是什么
What was that?
辐射警告罢了
Just a radiation warning.
预报器太敏感了
The detector's a little over-sensitive.
我才不会担心
I wouldn't worry about it.
我要回舰桥那边了
I've got to get back to the bridge.
你自己看着办吧
I'll leave you to it.
我们来到这个星系  正值战乱
We came to this galaxy during the war.
幽灵人和古人忙于战事
With both the wraith and the ancients occupied,
我们可以自由地进行试验
We were free to conduct our experiments.
不幸地
Unfortunately,
战事结束得
The hostilities came to an end
比我们预期要早
Sooner than we thought,
还引发了意料外的结果
And with an unexpected result.
你们把宝押在了古人身上
You were betting on the ancients.
他们或许会囚禁你们
They may have tried to shut you down,
但不至于将你们斩尽杀绝
But at least they wouldn't exterminate you.
幽灵人不能容忍
The wraith do not tolerate
比他们拥有的
The presence of advanced technologies
更先进技术的存在
Other than their own.
我们意识到事态严重的时候
Before we knew what was happening,
已是面临攻击的时候了
We were under attack.
第一场交战  我们失去了星际战舰
We lost our intergalactic ships in the first battle,
然而我们没有资源
And we did not have the resources
再造新的
To build more.
你们是怎么逃生的
So how did you survive?
我们别无选择
We had no choice
只有遗弃了我们的聚居地
But to abandon our settlements
撤到别的地方
And retreat to a place
一个幽灵人找不到的地方
Where the wraith could not look for us,
一个被毒气包围的星球
A planet with a toxic atmosphere.
听起来...不错
Oh. that... sounds nice.
开始的时候还可忍受
It was tolerable at first.
借助简单的呼吸装置
We were able to survive
我们可以存活
Using simple breathing apparatus.
但经过万古的时期
But over the eons,
环境变得越来越艰苦了
The environment has grown so harsh
连我们的盔甲
That not even our armored exoskeletons
也毫无作用了
Can protect us now.
所以你们又回到这个星系
So you ventured back into the galaxy,
来到了这里
And that's when you came across this place.
我们知道这是古人所建的  也知道为何所建
We knew it was built by the ancients, and why,
但是我们不能激活
But we were unable to activate it
除非有你的帮助
Until you came along.
很遗憾
Look, i-- I'm sorry
得知你们过去的岁月都困在被毒气
That you were trapped on a poisonous planet
围绕的星球
For the last 10,000 years.
真的
I really am.
我知道滋味不好受
I'm sure it was awful.
但是却不能作为杀戮的借口
But that doesn't justify what you're doing.
我的族人正在死亡
My people are dying.
事实上  就像你所说的  必须壮大本族
The fact that, as you tell us, our brothers are already gone,
而我们的亲缘已经绝迹
Only reinforces the need.
不行此着  我们的整个文明
If we do not do this, our whole civilization,
上百万年的历史
A hundred thousand years of history,
就要灰飞烟灭
Will be wiped out forever.
我绝不能眼看这发生
I cannot allow that to happen.
凯勒医生
Dr. keller.
是你在搞破坏?
You're the saboteur?
是的
That's right.
你的武器呢
Where's your weapon?
武器?
My weapon?
是的
Yes.
破坏水晶盘子的那个武器
The one you used to destroy the crystal trays.
我把它藏起来了
I ditched it.
你以为我会来白白送死吗
You really think I'd want it ending up in your hands?
以我为敌  愚蠢之极
Oh, it's foolish of you to see me as the enemy.
当真  为何
Really? why's that?
我是奉谢帕德上校之名行事
I'm on a mission from your colonel sheppard.
这点我十分怀疑
I seriously doubt that.
说来话长
It is a long story,
他和我们之间
But he has requested
关于一个危险的目标达成了中立
That we neutralize a very dangerous target.
你为什么要控制飞船
Then why did you take over the ship?
为什么伤害我们的人
Why did you attack our crew?
如我所言  说来话长
As I said, it is a long story.
然而  这项任务时间紧急
The mission, however, is time-sensitive,
你们给了我们一个烂摊子
And you have handed us a major setback.
超光速推进系统  武器  防护盾
Hyperdrive, weapons, shields--
都不能用了
They are all down.
真遗憾
That's a real shame.
是的
It is
顾及到成千上万的
Considering that hundreds of thousands
人类
Of humans
可能因此而死
Could die because of it.
我想  以后你肩上的担子
I would think that will weigh heavily on you
可要变重了
In the future.
你这是什么意思
What are you talking about?
超光速推进系统恢复
Hyperdrive's coming back up.
武器呢
And weapons?
不可复原  对我们来说已经不再派得上用场了
Irreparably damaged. they're no good to us anymore.
我猜  你是不能完成任务的了
I guess you won't be able to finish the mission, then.
总会有办法的
Oh, we'll find a way.
返回超空间
Get us back into hyperspace
把她带去和其他人一起
And get her down with the others.
没事吧
You okay?
我以为你死了
I thought you were a goner.
我没事
I'm all right.
我的意思是  他们需要我  你就没什么价值
I mean, they need me. you're kind of expendable.
我还以为
I just figured--
我明白你的意思
Yeah, I got what you meant by "goner".
他们想怎样
What did they want?
事实上  聊天
Uh, to talk, actually.
谈得如何
Oh. how did that go?
他们是阿斯加德族
They're asgard.
真的?
For real?
是从我们的老相识那里
Yeah, a faction that broke off from the guys we knew
分离出来的一个小派系
Thousands of years ago.
那些盔甲下面的  就是他们了
They're the ones inside the suits.
这我倒没料到
I did not see that one coming.
跟幽灵人也是对头
Apparently no fans of the wraith, either.
那他们肯关掉那设备么
Are they going to shut off the device?
不
Um, no.
那我也不操心了
Then I don't care.
总之这东西要是开着
As long as that thing is on,
就得死一大片
Then millions of people could die.
话说回来  我貌似找到出去的办法了
Besides, I think I've figured a way out of here.
真的吗
Really?
这是个古人设备
This is an ancient facility,
罗德尼·麦凯对古人设备
And rodney mckay knows a thing or two
还是略知一二的
About ancient facilities.
要知道  临床证实
It has been clinically proven--
用第三人称来指代自己
Referring to yourself in the third person
通常是精神错乱的前兆
Is a sign of mental instability.
应该说狐狸般的狡猾才对
Mentally unstable like a fox!
看看  计划这样
Okay, so, here's the plan.
我把起火警报的线路烧断
I blow the fire-monitoring fuse.
系统瞬间瘫痪
The system suddenly goes dead,
就会自动认定是起火了
It assumes there could be a fire,
然后探测到房间里的生命迹象
Detects lifesigns inside the room,
出于安全考虑  门就会自动打开啦
It unlocks the doors for safety.
干的妙
Good job.
还好他们把你带回来了
Good thing they brought you back when they did,
要不我就以为你死定了
Because I assumed you were dead
准备走了都
And I was going to leave.
-我命好  -不用谢我
Lucky me.Yeah, you're welcome
然后接下来我们干什么
So, what do we do now?
我们得把那设备关了
We've got to shut down the device.
要怎么做
How do we do that?
...即兴发挥吧
We'll just... we'll improvise.
对头!
Right.
托德没有杀了你
Todd didn't kill you.
可你差点害死我
No, but you almost got me killed.
我从来没在靶场以外的地方
I've never fired one of these
玩过这个
Outside of the range before.
你很棒
You did great.
若楠  干的好
Ronon. good work.
还没完呢
It's not over yet.
大厅里集结了军队
There's an armory down the hall.
我们得尽量找人
We need everyone we can.
我们要把船夺回来
we're taking the ship back
我们现在去控制室
we'll get to the device control room
你要自投罗网么
you're calling the soldiers
我们分散一下他们的注意力嘛
then we'll create a diversion
我们可以去能量补给站
Okay, uh, we go to the power relay station,
弄一个大爆炸
We create a massive explosion.
我没看出来这怎么叫转移注意力了
I never got how that made a good diversion.
什么
What?
你想把控制室的坏蛋都扫干净  对吧
You want to clear the device control room of bad guys, right?
当然
Yes.
那你为什么会觉得  如果有大爆炸
Why assume if there was a massive explosion
人们就一定会冲过去看呢
People would run towards it?
我就会呀
I would.
我持保留意见
I rest my case.
不好意思  我可是个大好人
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm a good person.
我会想把人们从火里救出来
I'd want to save people from the fire,
然后看看到底是怎么回事
Maybe figure out what was going on.
可是我会继续重兵把守
I'd order more guards to protect the one room
因为我觉得是有人故意制造混乱
I thought whoever is blowing things up
想偷溜进来
Probably wants to get to.
制造爆炸
Explosion diversions
是最基本的转移注意力的办法了
Are the very cornerstone of diversions.
没有更好一点的么
You don't have any better ideas?
没有了
I don't have any better ideas, yes.
哦  老天  别杀我
Oh, my god. please don't kill me.
我还有用
You need me.
罗德尼?
Rodney?
是我们...我们还有用
Us, us. you need us.
那设备需要细致保养
The device needs constant care.
只有我知道怎么操作它的
True, I'm the only one who knows how to work it--
我这么说了还是要杀我吗
What am I talking about killing for?
你们不是个暴力的种族
You're not a violent race.
或许你们有更让人惊讶的地方
You may have stunned us--
罗德尼
Rodney.
超过我们之前所以为的
...more than we'd have liked, but--
这些只是盔甲而已
They're just suits.
盔甲套着的是有史以来最聪明的种族
Suits that house one of the smartest races ever.
我是阿斯加德族的迷
I've always been a big fan of the asgards.
我也有阿斯加德族的好朋友
Some of my best friends are asgards--
他们是空的
They're empty suits.
看?
See?
是的  我知道  我只是
Yeah. I know. I was--
只是什么...
You were...
算了  又不是什么重要的
Yeah, it's not important.
就我看来
From what I could tell,
这些盔甲不管谁穿都合适
The inside of the suits form around whoever's in them.
所有人都是一个型号...
One size fits all...
你确定都搞清楚了?
You sure you have all that figured out?
我有些鸟  比这难控制多了
I've flown birds a lot harder to manage than this one.
我很惊讶  拉林居然不发表意见
I'm surprised larrin didn't say anything.
拉林以前从来没提起过你
Larrin's never brought you up before today.
真的?  从来没有?
Really? never, huh?
没有
Nope.
我们就要出超空间了
We're about to come out of hyperspace.
大家准备好
Everyone, get ready.
看  我就说了吧
See, I knew this would happen.
要烧坏了
We burned it out.
可是我们也到了  不是吗
We got here, though, didn't we?
有代达罗斯的踪影吗
Any sign of the  daedalus?
没有  看起来是我们先到了
No. looks like we beat them.
这可是今天的第一个好消息
That's the first good news I've had all day.
等等
Wait,
有两辆飞船靠近
I've got two ships closing in.
升起防护盾
Shields up.
如有必要就开火
Fire at will.
或者来一些躲避招式
Evasive maneuvers might be good.
明白!
I'm on it.
这里是安全的!
Clear!
为什么我们一路上都没碰到他们
How come we haven't run into any of them yet?
我有不好的预感
I've got a bad feeling about this.
做一下生命迹象扫描
Do a lifesigns scan,
看看他们在那里
Find out where they are.
302第二舱有大量生命迹象
I have a mass of lifesigns in the second 302 bay.
他们退回到自己的船上了  但仍在舱里
They fell back to their ship. it's still in the bay.
他们为什么要这么做
Why would they do that?
难道他们看见我们武装起来了?
They saw we'd armed up?
不想冒死一战?
Didn't want to risk a fight?
这听来不像托德
That doesn't sound like todd.
我去看看
I'm going to check it out.
带我们离开超空间
Take us out of hyperspace.
怎么了
What is it?
他们把飞行控制加密了
They locked us out of flight controls.
能破解吗
Can you get us back in?
不会这么快
Not quickly.
他想干什么
What's he got planned?
把设备关了得花多长时间
Okay, how long to get the device shut down?
五分钟
Five minutes.
然后你盯着...
All right, look. you watch the--
噢  搞什么鬼
Oh, come on!
什么  现在是什么情况
What? what now?
这些人肯定是被吓过
Well, something must have spooked them.
为什么这么说
Why?
除去密码不说  想进入这个工作站...
Well, aside from encrypting the access to this workstation...
这个你可以破解的呀
Yeah, but you can break that.
这是很关键  可是大家也都知道
Yeah, in a heartbeat, but, as they very well know,
没有控制匙  就不能对机器进行操作啊
You can't operate this machine without the control key.
看  那个从杰纳斯实验室偷走的东西
Look-- the thing they stole from janus' lab
就是用来启动用的
To begin with.
被他们拿走了
They've taken it.
搞定一个了  还有一个
One down, one to go.
我在瞄准正前方的那艘飞船
I'm picking up a third ship headed right for us.
非常好
Wonderful.
就差一点点  它飞进超空间了
That was close. it flew into hyperspace.
什么
What?
等等  又一个窗口打开了
Hold on,I've got another window opening.
它们现在在我们正后方
They're coming right back at us.
这玩得是哪门子战术
What kind of messed-up battle technique is that?
这有点过时了吧
It's quite a bit out,
现在还不在星球附近
Nowhere near the planet yet.
等等  这是代达罗斯号
Wait... it's the  daedalus.
呼叫他们
Contact them.
我们需要帮忙
We're going to need the help.
谢帕德中校?
Colonel sheppard?
真是惊喜啊  看到你们
Surprised to see all of you guys.
我们也是
Same here.
我在游历者...
Look, I'm on a travelers--
我在游历者的飞船上
I'm on a travelers ship.
我们正和敌方交战
We've engaged the enemy.
你把代达罗斯号抢回来了?
Have you gotten the  daedalus back?
我们需要支援
Because we're going to need the help.
托德让我们的  没怎么抢...
Todd let us take her back without so much as a fight.
因为他把飞行控制锁起来了
But he's locked us out of the controls
还撤退到了302舱
And retreated to one of the 302 bays.
见鬼了他这是什么意思
Why the hell would he do that?
他比谁都希望把这地方摧毁掉
He needs that place destroyed more than anyone.
伍尔希长官?
Mr. woolsey, sir?
怎么了  马克斯
What is it, marks?
我们一旦飞出了超空间
Sir, the second we came out of hyperspace,
一个预先设定好的子空间路线就会自动启动
A pre-programmed sub-routine kicked in.
意味着...
Meaning...
我们确定了设备的位置
Our main scanners located a facility on the planet
就同时把导航系统捆绑启动了
And immediately locked the guidance system into it.
飞船会飞向attero设备
It's taking us to the attero device.
而且
In a way...
长官  这是一个冲撞性程序
Sir, it's programmed a collision course.
这就是他摧毁设备的办法
That's how he's going to destroy the facility,
拉我们一起陪葬
By ramming us into it.
难道就不可能直接减掉它的能量
Can't we just power down the entire facility?
开灯关灯都还需要
You can't do much more than turn the lights off and on
一个零部件呢
Without the component thing.
我们必须得做些什么啊
We have to do something.
等等
Wait a second.
这些盔甲  是能够保护穿着者
These suits were designed
对抗恶劣环境的  对吧
To protect the wearer from harsh environments, right?
技术上来说  是的
Technically, yes.
那我有一个非常馊的馊主意了
Then I have a really terrible idea.
噢不
Oh, no, no.
你应该不是在想
You're not thinking
我以为你在想的东西吧
What I think you're thinking.
那里的辐射应该非常强
The radiation in there would be pretty extreme.
更不用说这放电的东西
Not to mention those electrical discharges
看起来非常不友好啊
Look pretty unfriendly, but...
是的  但它有个控制晶体
Yeah, but the antenna has a control crystal.
如果我们可以人为地拿掉它...
If we could pull it manually...
大概有5比5的几率我们可以做到
It's 50-50 we even get that far.
我觉得只有3比7
I'd go 30-70,
但我没更好的主意了
But I don't have a better idea,
还有这身行头  应该能保护我们
And the suits, they should protect us.
我们破坏了飞船的武器装备
We disabled the ship weapons.
你们做的?
You did?
若楠做的
Ronon did, yeah.
他们没办法了
They didn't have any other choice.
只有用飞船去撞坏那设备
Ramming the facility with the ship
才最有可能把它除掉
Is the only sure-fire way to take it out.
还同时把我们都害死了
Killing all of us in the process.
我不觉得他会担心这点
I don't think he's that worried about us.
他们刚刚对302号舱减了压
They just depressurized the 302 bay.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
我们就解决了它吧
Let's just get this over with.
你知道的  我们没必要两个都去
You know we both don't have to go in there.
如果你不幸
Well, when you get killed
被电流击中了
By one of those discharges,
必须有人来完成这项工作  所以
Someone's going to have to finish the job, so...
哇  真是振奋人心的谈话  谢谢
Oh, great pep talk. thanks.
我很确定
I'm pretty sure
我们得避开这些电流
We want to avoid those touching us.
多谢师傅
Thanks, coach.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
我必须选对
I have to pull the right one
否则它就爆炸了
Or the antenna explodes.
快点
Hurry up.
但还是要选对
But get it right.
代达罗斯号还有多久会撞击表面
How long before the daedalus hits the surface?
最多1分钟
A minute, tops.
飞船上有多少人
How many people on board?
大概200
Couple hundred.
听着  我有个主意  但你要相信我
Look, I've got an idea, but you'll have to trust me.
好
All right.
泽兰卡  米拉
Zelenka, Mila...
我要你开启超光速推进系统
I need you to open up the hyperdrive
30秒之内
In 30 seconds.
我们要做个短距离的跃迁
We're going to have to make a short jump.
不可能
Impossible.
没问题
Not a problem.
你能做到的  马克斯
You can do this, marks.
我们都靠你了
We're all counting on you.
我快要好了
I've almost got it.
我们进入大气了
We're entering the atmosphere.
马克斯
Marks...
好了
Okay.
什么也没发生
Here goes nothing.
丹尼尔
Daniel!
怎么了
What just happened?
欢迎回来
You're welcome.
你们做了什么
What did you do?
只是开了一个够我们两艘船
I just opened up a hyperspace window
用的超空间窗口
Big enough for the both of us.
我们刚刚穿过了星球
We just traveled through the planet.
搞定了
i got it.I'm back in.
我们又能控制飞船了
We've got control of the ship.
还不算太晚
And not a moment too late.
他们又找到我们了
They found us again.
火力全开
Give them everything you've got.
好
Okay.
你还好  你没事的
You're okay, you're okay.
又错了
Wrong again.
你关了吗
Did you turn it off?
我关了  是我们  是你
I did-- we did-- you did.
你哪儿受伤了
Look, where does it hurt?
浑身都是
Everywhere.
我想这里附近没医院吧
I don't suppose there's a hospital nearby?
我想  我们要自己解决了
I'm-- I'm pretty sure we're on our own.
很好
Good.
但是好的一面是
Look, on the bright side,
我们俩在大概5天内都会脱水致死
We'll both be dead of dehydration in, like, five days,
到时候你就不用再忍受我了
So you won't have to put up with me for much longer.
我  我很糟糕  罗德尼
I'm, uh, I'm pretty busted up, rodney.
我想我  坚持不了那么久
I don't... I don't think I'm going to make it that long.
我知道这看起来不像
Okay, um, I know it may not seem like it,
但我想告诉你  我真的很尊...
But I want you to know I really res--
感谢上帝
Oh, thank god.
很高兴看见你们
I sure am glad to see you two.
他伤得很重
He's badly hurt.
你有身新装扮
That's a new look for you.
你知道我的
Well, you know me,
功能性大过时尚性
It's function over fashion.
那些设备还在运作吗
Is the device still active?
没了这个就不行
Not without this.
这是设备上的主要的控制晶体
It's the facility's main control crystal.
这还不够
That's not good enough for me.
谢帕德中校
Colonel sheppard,
我们找回麦凯·博士和杰克森了
We have drs. mckay and jackson.
但我们的武器装备还没恢复
Our weapons are not operational.
你能不能确保下
Can you please see to it
我们不用再
That we never have to deal
担心attero设备了
With the attero device again?
我正在确定它的坐标
I'm locked on to its coordinates.
开火
Opening fire.
夷平了
Leveled.
很好
Good.
我们回去吧
Let's go home.
你能不能  帮我拉下拉链
Well, you want to... unzip me?
我会找个开罐器
I'll look for a can opener.
泽兰卡对飞船的修补起了很大的作用
Zelenka has been a big help with ship repairs.
我们应该尽快让她准备起飞
We should have her ready to fly in no time.
然后呢
Then what?
找个新的聚居地
Start a new settlement, I guess.
这听上去不错
That's good to hear.
你告诉拉林  我会
You tell larrin I'll help you
尽全力帮你们
With whatever you need.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们会再联系的
We'll be in touch.
好  保持联系
Yeah. I'm sure you will be.
告诉拉林她不必等着有什么紧急情况发生
Tell larrin she doesn't need to wait
才肯过来拜访一次
For the next galactic emergency To drop by.
我朋友都安全的时候
I'm a lot more charming
我也更和蔼一点
When my friends aren't about to die.
拉林可不是这么说的
That's not what larrin said.
看  她果然提过我
See, she does talk about me!
时不时地
Every now and again.
她说了什么
What does she say?
干嘛  连个提示都没有?
What, not even a hint?
你好
Hey.
你今天都忙完了?
You all done for the day?
库尔医生替了我的班
Uh, dr. cole's taking my shift. yeah.
想弄点吃的吗
Want to get something to eat?
听着
Um, listen,
我很高兴你一起参加了这次的任务
Um, I'm really glad you came on the mission.
如果没有你  我们可能都死了
I mean, without you there, we'd... probably all be dead.
但是...
But...
我只是想澄清一下  因为...
I just want to be clear, because, um...
我只是想你知道
I just want you to know,
我对...另一个人比较有兴趣
That, uh, I'm kind of... interested in somebody else.
所以呢
So?
我只是不想你误...
I just didn't want to give you the wrong--
没有  我只是想拿点吃的
Didn't. I just, um, wanted to get something to eat.
好的  我只是以为
Okay, because I thought--
是啊  所以你想错了
Yeah, well, you're wrong.
好
Okay.
好了
你还要去...
Do you still want to go--
不了  我还是...
Uh, no. I should probably...
我要走了
I should go.
你好
Hey.
感觉怎么样
How are you?
吃个水果杯都疼
Well, it hurts to eat this fruit cup.
那就别吃水果杯
Don't eat the fruit cup, then.
谢谢啊
Thank you, groucho.
听着  不是我不欢迎来访
Listen, not that I don't appreciate the visits,
只是你不是应该在想办法
But shouldn't you be trying to figure out a way
防止阿斯加德族人再来吗
To keep the asgards out of the shield again?
先你一步  不会再有这种事了
One step ahead of you. that won't happen again.
那很好
Oh. good.
你觉得他们不会再来找我们了?
You don't think they'd make a run at us again?
我不确定
Well, I'm not sure,
但我们的确是毁了他们的计划
But we did ruin the one plan they had
他们本可以自由地在星系活动
To feel free in this galaxy.
他们可能会怀恨在心吧
They might hold a grudge.
希望不要
Well, let's hope not.
我想我也不会留下查明这件事了
I don't think I'll be around to find out, though.
是的  我听说他们要把你送回地球
Yeah, I heard they're sending you back to earth.
是的  我需要点好的治疗和恢复
Yeah, I guess I need some major patching up and recovery.
兰德更希望我会地球做而不是这里  所以...
Landry prefers I do that there instead of here, so...
代达罗斯号从老的星门桥
The daedalus has already picked up a gate
那边选了一个门
Left over from the old gate bridge,
我们这会谈的时候  我的队伍正在安装测试
And my team is installing it as we speak,
马上就可以送你回家了
So we should have you home in no time.
那很好
That's good.
真是...好
That is good.
是啊  所以
Yes. so...
这一切真是  独特
Well, it's been... unique.
是的  当然
Yes, it has. it sure has.
但我还是要说声谢谢
But I do want to say thank you
为了你说你尊敬我
For, um, saying that you respected me
在你以为我快死了的那会儿
When you thought I was about to die back there.
等一下  我没这么说过
Excuse me? I said no such thing.
你说了
Yeah, you did.
你说
You were, like, um,
我知道这看起来不像
"i know it may not seem like it,
但我真的很尊敬你
But I really respect you,"
这对我而言意义很大
And that means a great deal to me.
我想我没把话说完
I don't believe I ever finished that sentence.
你还能怎么把它说完
How else would you have finished that sentence?
我会说  后悔
I would have said "regret."
我想说我很后悔你在那儿
I would have said I really regret you being here
因为这一切就都不会发生了
Because none of this would have happened...
如果那样
Otherwise.
你对将死之人就只说这些
So you can only give compliments to the dying?
这是一个我仍需加强的地方
It's something I'm working on.
你想不想尝尝这些
Do you want to try any of this?
哦  油炸的
Ooh, fries.
是的是的
Yeah, yeah.
多吃点吧  拿到那边去
Dive right in, take the-- take the deal there.